Poomagal C T

DATA SCIENTIST

🔀 ctpoomagal@gmail.com 👂 Doha, Qatar in https://www.linkedin.com/in/poomagalct

https://poomagal.github.io

SUMMARY

A professional with four years of experience in Python, Data science, web application development and testing until production deployment, developing a wide range of automation tools with agile scrum. To understand business use cases and requirements from clients and convert them into a well articulated problem statement and explain to the project teams. To provide the mentorship required for the other team members of the team. To lead and support various adhoc projects, as needed, in support of organizations business strategy.

SKILLS

Python, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Seaborn,	• • • •	MySQL, PostgreSQL & MongoDB	• • • • •
Matplotlib, PyTorch Statistics & Machine Learning	• • • • •	CI/CD- AWS, Azure, GCP, Jenkins	
		Dockers, Kubernetes	
C, C++, HTML, Java MATLAB		Flask, Django, Streamlit	
Github, SVN, Clearcase	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet	PowerBI & Google Data Studio	
		TCP/IP, CAN, DNS & HTTP	

PROJECTS SUMMARY

Thought Leadership BOT

End-to-End Project Jun 2023 - Jun 2024

An Al assisted ChatBOT based on telegram with the integration of API and added intelligence.

Page Speed Insights Analyser

End-to-End Project Jun 2023 - Jun 2024

A complete Analysis preperation about the Google Page Speed Insights Data via API and delivery of the same as a custom dashboard to the individual clients.

Python Based Projects

Domain Expiry Reminder, Zoom Automation, Bulk indexing Tool, HTAccess Generator, Review Scrappers, Customized Discord BOT, Meeting Reminder BOT, GTM Trigger Monitor and Review & Rating Analyzer. Jun 2023 - Jun 2024

Machine Learning Based Projects

Article Web Scrapping, Al Virtual Assistant, Customer trained ChatBOT for customer support, Domain Specific **Keyword Extraction**

Present

PATENT

Indian Patent Grant Title:

A Hardware Implementation of Secret Key Generation Using Multiple Chaotic Maps with Secure Hash Algorithms for 5G & Beyond Applications.

Name of Patentee: Poomagal C T and Sathish kumar G A & Patent Grant Number: 491362.

EXPERIENCE

Automation Analyst

Digital SEO - Chennai, Jun 2023 - Jun 2024

- Responsible for requirement gathering, solution designing & development and delivery of an outage of the projects/web applications.
- Developed scripts using python, html, css and integration with postgresql to deliver the features as microservice over fast API, Flask and streamlit.
- Designed interactive multiple front end application using streamlit and python.
- Handled & managed entire backend of development and deployment for all the automation projects in my working period.
- Developed interactive dashboards using tools like Power BI, Looker Studio and Python libraries like Matplotlib, Seaborn.

Research Fellow

Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO) Funded LAB - Sri Venkateswara College of Engineering - Chennai Dec 2017 - Nov 2019

- Designed theoritically, developed code from the scratch and deployed in ISRO server for three novel Cryptographic Key Exchange Algorithms using C++, Python and Matlab.
- Developed and configured the complete hardware setup for the above three Algorithms.
- Collaborated with scientists to resolve issues, code-related queries and perfect allignment of the project.
- · Preparation of various proposals, reports, presentations and analysis related to the research works.
- Presented to the Scientists at ISRO for three times at Annual Review Meeting on yearly basis held at Space Application Centre (SAC), ISRO, Ahmadabad, India.

Engineer Trainee

Cognizant Technology Solutions Pvt Ltd - Chennai Jul 2014 - Jun 2015

- Managed continuous deployment of PaaS Honda AHM project with two iterations per week.
- Received appreciation for automated over 10+ batch jobs in VmWare desktop, which resulted in the monthly cost/time saving in business by having deployment and tracking of database.
- Received appreciation for started solely supporting to developers within a week from joining the project, as a fresher.
- Collaborated with clients and developers to diagnose problems and implement configuration requirements and solutions.
- Developed Python automation scripts for the continuous deployment in Jenkins.

EDUCATION

Doctorate

Anna University Jul 2015 - Sep 2023

Master of Engineering

Anna University Aug 2012 - Jun 2014

Bachelor of Engineering

Anna University Aug 2008 - Jun 2012

PERSONAL SKILLS

High organizational and Leadership skills

Creative and Innovative Thinking

Motivation to learn

••••

Result-oriented
Enthusiasm & optimism
Communication &
Presentation Skills



CERTIFICATION

• Full Stack Data Science and Machine Learnig.

• Hardware & Networking.

LANGUAGES

Tamil

English

Hindi

